Benjamin Roberts

Business Analyst/Macro Developer - EdR, Inc.

Memphis, TN 38119 benrobertsmemphis@gmail.com - 901.292.4887

Experienced in programming, data management, reporting, and small teams management. Strong analytic, organizational, customer service, and communication skills. Adept at problem solving and creative thinking.

Languages:

VBA, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby, SAS

Software/Tools:

Excel, Access, JDE, ReportsNow, SAS Base/EG/macros, SAP Business Objects, SharePoint, Git/Git- Hub, Sublime Text, Wordpress, Joomla

Experienced in development of websites and web apps for local bands, artists, blogs, and coursework.

Led analysis and contributed to operations projects resulting in over \$8 million in increased revenue and a long-term, sustained decrease in accounts receivable.

Responsible for the automation of more than 40 hours' worth of manual processes resulting in reduced overhead, fewer errors, and faster response times. Automation achieved through a combination of scheduled tasks, stored procedures, and programming.

Aided in the transition from legacy reporting tools to new reporting and analysis tools by fostering communication between the business and IT, developing business requirements, assisting in ETL, data / report requirements development, writing document spec, designing and building new reports.

Created documents and conducted training for end users in SAS, SQL, and Excel.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst - Macro Developer

EdR Collegiate Housing - Memphis, TN - October 2015 to Present

Develops and implements operational / accounting reports for internal and external stakeholders

Designs, develops, implements, and maintains custom VBA Macros used to automate data extraction, report development, and report formatting

Extracts information from JDE databases regular/adhoc reporting and data conversion projects Gathers and analyzes business requirements for reporting needs

Ensures that information is presented accurately and in a clear, concise, and business-relevant manner Reconciles data and tests to validate and verify accuracy

Business Systems Analyst - Data Management Specialist

Accredo - Express Scripts - Memphis, TN - February 2012 to October 2015

Designed and developed reports and data extracts for business users to aid in the tracking and analysis of KPI, sales, revenue, productivity, and reimbursement data using SAS, SQL, Excel dashboards, Access databases, Business Objects, VBA, macros, and SharePoint sites.

Responsible for report automation using SAS, SQL, Business Objects, HTML/CSS, ColdFusion, and VBA. Worked cross-functionally and with all levels of management to determine and define business requirements for reporting tools and data extracts/analysis.

Act as liaison between Snr Management, IT, and multiple COE's in support of projects, analysis, and process improvement.

Analyzed data and financial metrics to identify trends, anomalies, and inefficiencies.

Account Executive

Robert Half Technology - August 2011 to February 2012

Developed and grew client base through marketing services and needs analysis. Responsible for properly servicing and maintain client accounts.

Agent

Tri-States Financial - February 2011 to July 2011

Expanded current business through telemarketing and on-site client visits.

Determined clients' current needs and helped to anticipate future needs in order to make appropriate recommendations.

Helped clients navigate complicated financial contracts.

Intern

New York Life - September 2010 to January 2011

Expanded current business through telemarketing and on-site client visits.

Determined clients' current needs and helped to anticipate future needs in order to make appropriate recommendations.

Explained insurance policies and annuities.

Provided exceptional customer service.

Full-time student

University of Memphis - August 2009 to December 2010

Marketing Director

Smartliving, Inc - March 2005 to July 2009

Managed sales and accounting teams and coordinated with other departments. Provided regular reports and sales analysis to management and other functional areas.

Negotiated short-term and long-term contracts with local/national vendors and customers. Trained sales, service, and warehouse staff.

EDUCATION

B.B.A. in Business Finance STRENGTHSFINDER

University of Memphis 2010 Achiever • Analytical • Competition • Context • Restorative

SKILLS

HTML (10+ years), Excel (10+ years), Access (5 years), VBA (4 years), Data Analysis (4 years), SQL (3 years), SAS (3 years), Data Management (3 years), CSS (2 years), Report Automation (2 years), JavaScript (1 year), Ruby on Rails (1 year), PHP (1 year), ColdFusion (1 year), SQL Server (1 year), C++ (1 year), Pascal (1 year)

LINKS to coursework and side projects.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/thisbenroberts https://github.com/ThisBenRoberts

http://www.thisbenroberts.com https://twitter.com/ThisBenRoberts

http://careerfoundry.com/users/ben-roberts http://careerfoundry.com/users/ben-roberts

https://www.freecodecamp.com/thisbenroberts